Tohtsuki Resort Hotel: Tohtsuki Rikyuu
If you cannot finish serving our guests' dinners within the next sixty minutes,
（関守平(せきもりひとし)）
60分以内に―
夕食の提供を
完遂できない者は―
you will be expelled on the spot.
その時点で退学とする
Mito Ikumi
12 Servings Left
Yoshino Yuuki
18 Servings Left
（吉野悠姫(よしのゆうき)）え… ええ…
Sakaki Ryouko
17 Servings Left
I'm not done yet! Not done!
（榊涼子(さかきりょうこ)）
終わらない！ 終わらない！
Takumi Aldini
2 Servings Left
（タクミ･アルディーニ）くうっ
Isami Aldini
5 Servings Left
Ibusaki Shun
15 Servings Left
Fifty's nothing to sneeze at.
（伊武崎峻(いぶさきしゅん)）さすがに多いな
Marui Zenji
22 Servings Left
Fifty!
（丸井善二(まるいぜんじ)）50食…
Here you go!
（田所恵(たどころめぐみ)）
お待たせしましたぁ
Finally, girl!
（大学生Ａ）
待ちかねたぞ 姉ちゃん！
はぐはぐはぐ　おお うめえ！
Wow, it's delicious!
I could eat this all day!
（大学生Ｂ）まだまだ食えるぞ！
Thank goodness. I'm glad they're eating a lot.
（恵）よかった
皆さん たくさん食べてくれてる
It's not greasy at all!
（大学生Ｃ）脂が全然しつこくない
It's not overcooked, either!
（大学生Ｄ）それでいて
パサパサしてない！
Great! Delicious!
（大学生たち）うまい うまい
うまい うまい！
I want seconds and thirds!
（大学生Ｅ）どんどんおかわりを！
All right!
（恵）よし　もっと頑張ろう！
Tadokoro Megumi
30 Servings Left
I'm going to try even harder!
Tadokoro Megumi
30 Servings Left
The Heavenly Recette
（薙切(なきり)えりなの鼻歌）
（えりな）ああっ！
（幸平創真(ゆきひらそうま)）あっ ど… お…
（えりな）あっ… ああ…
（創真）ああ 悪(わり)ぃ
Oops, sorry.
Y-Yukihira Souma!
ゆ… 幸平創真
ああん？
You all right, Nakiri?
（創真）
ああ 大丈夫か 薙切
どっか ひねったりしてねえか
Did you twist your ankle or anything?
（えりな）
触らないで！　１人で立てるわ
Don't touch me!
I can get up without your help!
What a blunder!
（えりな）不覚！
I let my guard down because I thought I was alone.
誰もいないと思って
油断してたら―
よりによって この男に
And he saw me like this, of all people!
I hope he didn't hear me.
まさか聞かれてないわよね
You seem to be in a really good mood, what with the humming and all.
にしても 鼻歌交じりで
随分ご機嫌だったなぁ
Humming?! Who, me?!
鼻歌？　誰が？
身に覚えがないけど！
What are you talking about?!
聞かれてた！
So he did hear me!
Well, I do get why you're so cheerful.
まあ 浮かれるのも分かるぜ
温泉だし お泊まりだからな
Here we are, staying a few nights at a hot spring.
I even brought cards and other stuff to play with.
俺も花札とかトランプとか
無駄に持ってきちまったよ
I'm not cheerful at all!
（えりな）私は浮かれてない！
I'm not like you.
君と一緒にしないで
I'd been told this is supposed
to be a camp straight out of hell,
地獄の合宿だとか
言われてるようだけど―
but I find it to be a boring, pointless excursion.
私にとっては退屈でしかない
下らない行事だわ
On the other hand, getting to see you expelled
まあ でも
君が何日目で脱落するか―
may prove to have some entertainment value.
それを眺めるのは
ささやかな余興かしらね
Sure, whatever.
よく言うぜ
ウキウキで歩いてたくせに
You were totally enjoying yourself just now.
Erina-sama!
（新戸(あらと)緋沙子(ひさこ)）えりな様～！
I'm sorry I took so long!
（緋沙子）
遅くなりました～
少々 手間取ってしまって…
It was more work than I'd anticipated—
Y-Yukihira Souma!
ゆ… 幸平創真～！
Large Communal Bath
What are you doing here?!
貴様 ここで何をしている？
Large Communal Bath
Oh, I pushed Nakiri down on the floor.
いやぁ
薙切を押し倒しちまって
On the
Floor
（創真）へっへっへっへ…
（えりか）あ～れ～
Oh, no!
What?!
Don't make it sound like something it wasn't!
誤解が生じる言い方しないで！
But I did, didn't I?
誤解じゃないだろ
こう 思いっきりボイーンと
I made you go all "boing" and stuff.
Boing?!
（緋沙子）ボイン？
（えりな）うわっ
Boing?!
Th-That's not true, Hisako!
ちっ 違うってば 緋沙子
God! Just get out of my sight already!
もう！
早くどこかへ行きなさいよ！
Fine, fine.
（創真）わあった わあった
Bathy bath, plungy plunge.
（創真）
風～呂だ 風呂だ
ざっぶざぶ～
Is everything all right?
あの 本当に大丈夫でしたか？
Yes!
問題ないわ　あなたも入浴を
済ませておいでなさい
Go take your bath.
Okay.
はい…
Oh, I managed to borrow them
from the front desk.
あ それとフロントで
借りてきましたよ トランプ！
Cards!
I would never waste my time
on something so frivolous!
そんな浮かれたもの
やりません！
Uh, what?
え？　あれ？
だって えりな様がさっき…
But Erina-sama, earlier...
Say, Hisako.
（えりな）ねえ 緋沙子
ここ トランプとかあるのかしら
Do you think they have cards here?
What?
Cards. Playing cards.
トランプよ トランプ
Cards? You want to play cards?
トランプ やりたいんですか？
We can play together, can't we?
２人なら できるでしょ？
You're right.
そう… ですね
フロントで聞いてみます
I'll try asking the front desk.
ウフッ
Isn't that what you said?
（緋沙子）
…って言ってましたよね？
I absolutely did not !
そんなこと言ってません！
Is something the matter?
（緋沙子）
あの… どうかなさいましたか？
No, there is not!
（えりな）どうもしてません！
Man, what's with her?
（創真）
まったく何なんだ あの女
相変わらず意味分かんねえ
Bath
Male
I still don't get what her deal is.
Bath
Male
Oh, well.
まあ いいや
ゆっくり湯につかろ
Gonna take my sweet time in the bath.
First one in, here I come!
一番風呂 いただきい！
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Doujima Gin
Tohtsuki Resort
Head Chef and Company Director
Uh...
Oh?
ん？　もう１人目が来たのか？
The first student's here already?
Sorry. Stretching in the bath
is part of my daily routine.
悪いな　入浴中の
肉体のメンテナンスは日課でね
At that moment, a thought formed in Souma's mind.
（ナレーション）
その時 創真は珍しく…
He's freakin' scary!
（創真）おっかね！
A thought that rarely occurred to him.
（ナレーション）…と思った
But it was only for a moment.
（ナレーション）
でも 一瞬だった
Man, and I was all revved up thinking I'd be the first one here.
んもう！　一番風呂だと思って
勇んで来たのに ガッカリっすわ
What a letdown!
アッハハハハ　悪い悪い
Sorry about that.
You'll have to settle for being the first student here.
学生の中では一番なんだから
それで手を打ってくれ
うーん しかし
去年といい今年といい―
I have to say, between last year and this year,
the academy has some very
good students in the pipeline.
なかなかいい学生が育ってるなぁ
Last year?
去年って？
The task of preparing fifty servings has been
assigned simultaneously at multiple locations.
（堂島）50食作りの試練は―
同じ時刻に
数カ所の厨房(ちゅうぼう)で一斉に行われる
It's obvious who completed that task the fastest.
誰が一番早くクリアするか
一目瞭然
Every year, I try to finish my bath
and leave before students show up.
俺は毎年 学生が風呂に来る前に
あがるようにしているんだが―
But last year, there was a student
who finished and showed up early too.
去年も１人
早々に作り終えた男が やって来た
Oh?
He's now the seventh seat in the Elite Ten.
（堂島）
今 遠月(とおつき)十傑の第七席にいる男だよ
Someone I'm quite familiar with.
（創真）知ってる人だった
He seemed promising as well.
奴も なかなかに
歯応えのある男だったな
That sounds like Isshiki-senpai all right.
（創真）ほほう
さすがは一色先輩だぜ
Hm?
Wait, she finished even earlier than I did?
待てよ　ってことは―
あいつは俺より早く
50食 仕上げたってことか
Speed isn't everything, of course,
早くクリアするだけが
全てではないが―
but it does say something about one's skills.
腕が立つことだけは確かだな
Thank you.
（緋沙子）
ありがとうございました
（フロント係）はい
You're welcome.
Oh, Hisako.
（えりな）ああ 緋沙子 やっぱり…
Actually...
I even brought cards and other stuff to play with.
いやあ 俺も花札とかトランプとか
無駄に持ってきちまったよ
I don't need them after all.
やっぱり要らないわ
Okay.
Nakiri Erina,
（堂島）薙切えりな
granddaughter of the academy's director.
学園総帥(そうすい)の孫娘
The God Tongue.
神の舌(ゴッドタン)
All of the academy's senior lecturers
have been at her disposal since her infancy.
赤ん坊の頃から
学園の主任講師を総動員
はう…
So-so.
She would refuse to eat anything except the most exquisitely made baby food.
（堂島）
彼女は洗練された離乳食しか
口にしなかった
Once when she was a child, she was made to taste several varieties of salt while blindfolded.
数種類の塩を 幼少時
目隠しで味見した時も…
Shoudo Island, Kagawa Prefecture.
香川県 小豆島
Noto Peninsula, Ishikawa Prefecture.
石川県 能登半島
Kuroshio City, Kouchi Prefecture.
高知県 黒潮町
She correctly identified each salt's origin.
（堂島）
その全ての産地を
言い当てたなど―
There are more stories than I can count about her God Tongue.
ゴッドタンと言うに
ふさわしい逸話は―
挙げれば切りがない
However, her ascendance as the youngest member
of the Elite Ten is founded on true talent.
だが 最年少で十傑に入った
その力は―
確かな技術に
裏づけされたものだ
If she continues at that level,
順当にゆけば 遠月(とおつき)学園
開闢(かいびゃく)以来 最高傑作の化け物に
she will become Tohtsuki's greatest masterpiece, a true monster.
But she's still a diamond in the rough.
まあ いずれにせよ まだ素材だ
Tohtsuki is a hellish place,
才ある者が集い
食らい合う人外魔境―
where those with talent throng
and devour one another.
それが遠月
Its depths are unfathomable.
この学園の底は深いぞ
存分に牙を磨け 少年
Sharpen your fangs, boy!
Yes, sir.
うっす
Yukihira!
幸平！　今回は後れを取ったが
次は こんなわけには…
You may have finished before me this time,
but I won't let that happen—
どっ！　堂島シェフ…
Chef Doujima?!
Ah, it seems I've soaked for too long.
うん　長居したな
俺は そろそろ行こう
I should get going.
At any event,
とにかく 合宿は
まだ始まったばかり
the camp is just beginning.
Be sure to take care of yourself physically.
体のメンテナンスは
しっかりとしておくんだ
Good luck.
明日からも頑張れよ
Thanks, Doujima-senpai.
あざっす 堂島先輩
（タクミ）
あ… ああ… がっ があ！
D-D...
あっ あの人が誰だか
分かってんのか？
Do you know who he is?!
Yeah, he's Doujima-senpai.
おう 堂島先輩だろ
You're right, but— Wait, that's not what I mean!
そうだけど…
あ いや そうじゃなくて…
How could you nonchalantly
shake hands with him, Yukihira?!
何 朗らかに握手してるんだよ
幸平！
Hm?
Yukihira?
（堂島）幸平？
I've heard that name before.
その名 どこかで…
Man, preparing fifty servings was exhausting!
（悠姫）いやあ～ 50食の課題
つっかれた～
I'm glad we all made it.
無事に みんな突破できて
よかったね～
This is what the next four days will be like.
こんなのが
あと４日続くのよね
They didn't call it the camp from hell for nothing.
地獄の合宿は
ダテじゃないわ
But when you're soaking in a hot bath,
でも お風呂に入ると 何だか
また頑張ろうっていう気になるよね
you find the energy to fight another day.
You brought that with you?
それ 持ってきたの？
ん？　エッヘヘ
I thought I should let him see the world.
せっかくだから
旅させようかなって
Phew.
にしても…
Still...
Wh-What?
な… 何よ
You're as audacious as ever,
相変わらずの
傍若無人ぶりですなぁ
aren't you, Sakaki-dono?
ああ～ん？　榊殿
Maybe the rice malt's working some magic.
もしかして麹(こうじ)が効くのかな？
Don't you start in on my bust too, Megumi.
恵まで じろじろ見ないの！
Look, it's seeing the world.
おお 旅してる
（恵）わあ～
Aw, silly boy.
もう～ おちゃめさんね
（悠姫）ぷあはっは！
Well, then.
さーって そろそろ行こっか
Time to get going!
Let's see the room that'd normally cost us 80,000 yen per night!
普通に泊まったら
１泊８万円以上の部屋に
Yoshino Yuuki
Hair-down Version
Wow!
ひゃっほー！
ウフフ
恵も寝転んでみたら？
Yeah!
Why don't you try it out too, Megumi?
（悠姫）
うえーい！　やっほい！
It's so fancy that I feel like
I'd jinx myself if I touched anything.
何だか 高級すぎて
バチが当たりそうだよ
ヘイヘーイ！
Fancy-schmancy!
豪華… すぎる… あはっ
Yuuki, you're embarrassing yourself.
悠姫 品がないわよ
うれしいのは分かるけど
I know you're happy, but...
U-Um...
（丸井）
あ… あのさあ…
Oh, Marui-kun.
あら 丸井君
若干 細くなった？
You look a little wasted.
Do I?
そうかい？
では そんな僕の話を聞いてくれ
Then why don't you hear what I have to say?
Let's call it a day and get some rest for tomorrow.
今夜は もう解散して―
明日に備え ゆっくり休もう
We're here!
（佐藤昭二(さとうしょうじ)･青木(あおき)大吾(だいご)）
オラァ！　来たぞお！
遊ぶぜえ！
Let's play!
Why do you guys keep coming to my room?!
だから 何でいつも
僕の部屋に集まるんだ！
All right!
よっしゃあ！
何やる？　何やる？
What should we do?
Daihinmin! 100 games!
（佐藤･青木）
大貧民 百番勝負！
F-Fine. It's on!
いいだろう　勝負だぁ！
Two minutes and fifteen seconds.
（伊武崎）２分15秒か
Their exhaustion overwhelmed them the moment they eased up.
（涼子）
疲れが一気に来たって感じね
Well, we can let them be till lights out.
（伊武崎）
ま 消灯時刻まで転がしとくか
You're not sleepy, Megumi?
恵は まだ眠くないの？
That's not like you.
珍しいわね
いつもなら早々に おねむなのに
You usually go to sleep early.
Yeah, it's weird.
うん おかしいよね
疲れてるのに目がさえてるんだ
I'm tired, but I'm still wide awake.
Well, you've been super focused the whole day.
ま １日中
気ぃ張ってたもんな
That's true.
えへ そうだね
でも たぶん それだけじゃなくて
But that's probably not the only reason.
I'm always so nervous in class.
（恵）私 いつも授業で
すごく緊張しちゃって―
I'm anxious the whole time,
worrying about messing up.
失敗したらどうしようって
焦ってばかりなんだけど―
But today, I managed to back
Souma-kun up just fine.
今日は創真君のサポートが
ちゃんとできたから…
Glad you liked it!
御粗末様！
So just a bit, just a tiny bit,
ほんのちょっと… ちょっとだけ
自信がついたような気がして
I'm starting to believe in myself.
And I'm kind of excited about that.
それでドキドキしてるの
But, you know, it's because Souma-kun gave me such good instructions!
あと えっとな 指示さ出してくれた
創真君のおかげで―
I really didn't do anything special!
あ… わたすは
なんも偉くねんだけども
That's not true.
I couldn't have made that dish if you
hadn't gathered the right ingredients,
田所が素材 集めてくれなきゃ
あの品はできなかったし―
and you cooked everything just fine.
調理もバッチリ
こなしてくれたじゃねえか
He's right.
そうよ
恵は やればできる子だもの
You're totally capable of rising to the occasion.
Be more confident, okay?
もっと自信持って　ね！
コップ16個～
Sixteen cups!
Wow!
Amazing!
Ultra fast rotation!
（創真）高速大回転～
Let me try too!
（涼子）あ 私もやってみたい～
Here it comes! Here it comes!
キテます キテます
Let me try!
I want to continue to be with them.
（恵）
もっと みんなと一緒にいたい
もっと料理が上手になりたいよ
I want to improve my cooking.
I'm going to try my best.
私 頑張るね
You're fired.
（四宮小次郎(しのみやこじろう)）クビだ
Camp Day 2 - 9:00 AM
Good morning.
（四宮）おはよう
79期卒業生の四宮だ
I'm Shinomiya, an alumnus
of the 79th graduating class.
Shinomiya Kojirou
Chef at French restaurant SHINO'S
This task involves preparing a dish of my choosing.
この課題では
俺が指定する料理を作ってもらう
You all have the recette, I hope?
ルセットは行き渡ったな
Shit, it's Chef Shinomiya.
（男子生徒Ａ）
最悪だ　四宮シェフかよ
I heard he expelled over thirty students yesterday.
（男子生徒Ｂ）昨日も30人以上
退学にしたらしいぜ
And he's assigned a recipe
that he came up with.
（男子生徒Ｃ）しかもお題が
四宮シェフ考案のレシピだなんて
Terrine of Nine Vegetables.
（ナレーション）
９種の野菜のテリーヌ
Though visually arresting with its nine vibrant vegetables,
色とりどりの野菜が美しく
華やかなイメージだが―
each vegetable requires its own
specific preparation and cooking time,
９種類の野菜それぞれに
違う下処理 火入れが必要
and none must overwhelm or
underwhelm its counterparts.
どの野菜が主張しすぎても
弱くなってもいけない
It is a herculean task to bring
all nine flavors together.
味をまとめ上げるのは
至難の業である
I chose one of my easier recettes.
俺のルセットのうち
割と簡単な料理をチョイスした
Would you prefer something
more challenging instead?
もっと難しい品のほうが
よかったか？
Damn him.
（男子生徒Ｄ）クッソ…
（男子生徒Ｅ）マジ殴りてえ
I want to punch him.
"Recette"?
ルセット？
It's the French word for recipe.
レシピのことだよ
Oh.
Also,
（四宮）それと…
（恵）あ？
you will not be working in teams for this task.
この課題ではチームは組まない
Each of you must prepare the dish individually.
（四宮）
１人でひと品 仕上げてもらう
（恵）う… あ… あ…
（四宮）調理中の情報交換や―
You may not share information
or help each other during this task.
助言は禁止だ
You will each choose your ingredients from the piles at the back of the kitchen.
食材は厨房後方の山から
任意で選び 使用してくれ
Lastly, a word of advice.
それから
１つアドバイスを贈ろう
You would do well to think of
everyone else as your enemies.
周りの奴ら全員―
敵だと思って取り組むのが
賢明だぜ
You have three hours.
（四宮）制限時間は３時間
Now...
それでは 始めろ
begin.
Ow! Get out of my way!
（男子生徒Ｆ）痛えな どけよ！
Screw that! I'll kill you!
（男子生徒Ｇ）
ふざけんな 殺すぞ！
Outta the way!
（男子生徒Ｈ）邪魔だ おら！
（男子生徒Ｉ）押すなよ！
Everyone's wild-eyed.
（恵）みんな 目が血走って
昨日よりも緊張感が すごいよ
The tension's even worse than yesterday.
But I can't be scared.
でも 怖がってなんか
いられない
I'm not going to let this get to me!
負けるもんか！
Okay!
よし！
（創真）よし
All right!
Um...
うんと… こっちだ！
This one!
I'm lagging behind everyone else,
（恵）
だいぶ出遅れちゃったけど
あとはカリフラワーがあれば…
but all I need now is some cauliflower.
Not this one, this one, or this one!
（恵）これも これも これも…
This slight discoloration...
酸化が始まって
わずかに色があせた―
All the ones that are left are in early stages of oxidization!
状態の悪い物しか残ってない
If I cook them as is,
このまま普通に調理したら―
the discoloration will become more pronounced,
アクのせいで
色が もっと悪くなって―
and the terrine's appearance,
a critical element of the dish, will suffer!
テリーヌの大事な
美しい見た目を損ねちゃう
Wh-What should I do?
ど… どうしよう…
Souma-kun—
創真く… はっ！
You may not share information nor help each other during this task.
（四宮）
調理中の情報交換や
助言は禁止だ
I can't.
（恵）ダメだ　創真君に
頼ってばかりじゃダメだよ
I can't rely on Souma-kun all the time.
I have to figure this out on my own!
私 独りで―
ちゃんと乗りきらなきゃ
How can I preserve the cauliflower's color?
カリフラワーの色を
保つには…
I've got it!
そうだ！
Hey, that's not what the recette says, is it?
（男子生徒Ｊ）
おい　それ ルセットと
違うんじゃないか？
Huh?
（男子生徒Ｋ）いや… ああ そうか
Oh, you're right.
You two, over there.
（四宮）そこの２人
I told you before.
（四宮）
言ったよな
情報交換も助言もするなって
Sharing information or
helping each other is not allowed.
Did you miss what I said?
聞いてなかったのか？
I-I didn't do anything like that!
え… い 今のは
そういうのじゃなくて…
He's right.
う… そうです　俺が ちょっと
間違ったのを教えてくれただけで
All he did was point out my small mistake.
So he did help you.
そういうのを
助言って言うんだよ
You've failed.
失格
Both of you are fired.
お前ら２人 クビだ
Start over!
作り直し
You're fired.
クビ　お疲れ
Good job.
P-Please!
（男子生徒Ｍ）
そ そんな…　もう１回…
もう１回 作り直しますから
I'll...
I'll make it over!
Do you have any ingredients?
（四宮）材料は あるのか？
You do not.
（四宮）
材料もない 時間もない
And time's almost up.
If you can remake the dish, you're a greater magician than I could ever hope to be.
それでも作れるって言うなら
お前 俺を超える魔術師だぜ
Fired!
クビ　クビ
Fired.
（男子生徒Ｎ）うう ひっく…
Yukihira Souma.
（創真）幸平創真です
Oh?
ほう
You pass.
（四宮）合格だ
I'm done!
できた！
９種の野菜のテリーヌ
The Terrine of Nine Vegetables!
あっ　もう時間が！
I'm almost out of time!
You're the last one.
お前で最後だな
T-Tadokoro Megumi.
たっ 田所恵です
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you for having me!
Tadokoro Megumi.
（四宮）田所恵　クビだ
You're fired.
That concludes our session.
以上で課題は終了だ
Those who passed should
prepare for the afternoon—
残った合格者は
午後の課題に備え…
E-Excuse me!
（恵）あっ あの！
Why?
どうして… どうして私の品
ダメなんでしょうか
Why was my dish unacceptable?
Ah.
ああ　傷み始めてるカリフラワーを
ゆでる時に―
You used wine vinegar when you boiled the oxidized cauliflower, didn't you?
ワインビネガーを
使ったんだろ？
You maintained its pristine color by using vinegar, which has a whitening effect.
漂白作用のあるビネガーで
きれいな色を保って―
Using vinegar in the seasoning also
enhanced the cauliflower's sweetness.
下味にも
ビネガーを使うことで―
カリフラワーの甘みを
引き立てている
The sweetness of the vegetables and the vinegar's mild acidity
野菜の甘みと
ビネガーの かすかな酸味が―
are in perfect harmony.
絶妙にマッチした味に
なっているな
Th-Then why?
え… なのに どうして？
Who said you could change the recette?
（四宮）
誰がルセットを
変えていいと言った？
This dish is intended to display the harmony created by the sweetness of each vegetable.
（四宮）このメニューは―
それぞれの野菜の甘みが作り上げる
ハーモニーを楽しむものだ
Nowhere in the recette did it say
to make use of acidity.
ルセットの中に―
酸味を生かすなんて文言が
１カ所でもあったか？
The dish you made is an entirely different beast.
お前が作ったのは
もはや全く別の料理
Presenting a dish that does not align with the task
merits a fail as a matter of course.
課題に沿わない料理を出せば
当然 失格
I hope that answer suffices.
納得したか？
It doesn't.
納得いかないっすね
It was what you'd call an unavoidable accident.
そりゃ不可抗力ってやつでしょ
There were ingredients that weren't fresh.
鮮度の落ち始めてる食材が
混じってたんだから
Besides, aren't we being treated as our senpais' employees during this time?
大体 俺らはこの課題の間―
先輩たちの従業員として
扱われるわけでしょ
As our boss, managing the ingredients is your responsibility, Shinomiya-senpai.
なら 食材管理の責任は
トップである四宮先輩にあるはず
Wouldn't that make this your fault as the chef?
そこんとこ シェフとしての
落ち度があるんじゃないです…
You brat.
ガキが 誰に向かって口きいてんだ
ああ？
Who do you think you're talking to?
You don't seem to get it,
so I'll explain it to you.
分かってないようだから
教えてやる
I added poor-quality cauliflowers on purpose
to limit the number of people who would pass!
状態の悪いカリフラワーは
わざと混ぜた
合格者を絞るためにな
Cauliflower is an ingredient that oxidizes quickly,
is easily damaged, and is difficult to prepare.
（四宮）
カリフラワーは
酸化しやすい―
Oxidizes Quickly
Easily Damaged
傷みやすい
調理しづらいの―
Difficult to Prepare
三拍子そろった食材の
１つだ
Any idiot who lost their cool and made a poor selection would fail.
冷静さを失い―
その目利きを怠ったマヌケは
漏れなく失格にした
That includes any laggards who fell behind
and couldn't secure a better one.
出遅れて いい物を確保できない
ノロマもな
That's why Tadokoro tried to
compensate by being creative!
だから 田所は
その遅れをカバーするために―
創意工夫して対応を
I am the chef here.
シェフは俺だ
Underlings like you have no right to make changes to my recette!
俺が作ったルセットに
手を加えることが―
下っ端に許されるわけねえだろ！
Listen up, underling.
いいか 下っ端
これ以上 俺に盾突くなら―
If you refuse to back down,
I can fire you too, on my authority as a chef.
シェフの権限で
お前もクビにしてやろうか
What?!
Souma-kun, it's okay!
創真君 もういいの！
I'm fine.
もう大丈夫だから
創真君まで退学になっちゃうべさ
You'll get expelled too.
Okay?
ね だからもう…
So stop.
Huh?!
I don't care about that crap right now!
エヘヘ　いいの
Really, it's okay.
Don't... Don't worry about me, so...
私の… 私のことは
もういいから
エヘへ…
Shinomiya-senpai, I'm sorry to bother you,
四宮先輩　すんません
最後に もう１個だけ
but there's one more thing.
What now, Monsieur Yukihira?
何だい ムッシュ･ユキヒラ
まだ何か文句でも？
Do you have another complaint?
No, it's a question, not a complaint.
いやあ 文句っつーか
質問なんすけど―
Does that Tohtsuki rule apply to alumni too?
遠月の あのルールって
卒業生にも適用されるんすかね
What are you talking about?
何の話だ？
Cooking Battles.
食戟(しょくげき)
Cooking Battle
If I beat you in a Cooking Battle,
食戟で あんたを負かしたら―
will you rescind Tadokoro's expulsion?
田所の退学
取り消してくんないすか
Next Episode
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
（丸井）
次回「食戟のソーマ」 11品目
the eleventh dish.
Are you okay, Marui?
（伊武崎）大丈夫か 丸井
Menu
The Magician from the East
The Magician from the East.
（丸井）
「東から来た魔術師」
フフッ
Ibusaki's never off.
（丸井）伊武崎 ハズレなし
（伊武崎）だな
Nope.
Yuuki has leveled up!
Pant